I've talked about this on the podcast
before but I have found this bug this
was one of the first bugs that I ever
one of the first criticals I ever
submitted um was a password reset token
that was being generated by
md5 uh of the user's email plus the
current Unix timestamp and I just
guessed that [__] dude I guessed it I
looked at that I did I guessed it
[Music]
all right I've I've had a thought um
while I was sitting on the toilet great
thank you thank you for starting the
episode that way that's lovely so you
know I was just thinking like the
bathroom definitely one of the most
like what's the word I'm looking for
looked under a microscope scre like
scrutinized scrutinized yeah most
scrutinized part of the house you know
because you're just sitting there you're
just you're just looking it oh there's a
this tiles missing grout there's a
little this wall you know there's a
place for perfection in the house it's
it's the bathroom I think just for for
perfectionism true yeah anyways that was
just I just that was a thought I had
well thank you for starting this uh this
podcast on information security and
hacking uh out with an analysis of what
parts of the house are most scrutinized
listen I'm just saying with our
backgrounds we could very easily do at
least one whole episode about
construction dude we absolutely could we
absolutely could that that that's going
to have to be a critical thinkers
exclusive I think episode of me and you
just yapping about real estate and uh
construction renovation and all that all
man we have time to play today there is
an absolute onslaught of awesome um
research that got published in the news
for this week so um let's hit the ground
running with that and of course we have
to start with our man
suou of course yeah there I think there
was some thread to that he's like man I
I've got this like thing that I need to
write up and like I just don't really
want to do it and then it was like a
comment under something and then that
comment like ratioed and blew up and was
like so roou ride it up please please
write up and I think this is the result
of that so way to go serou for actually
getting uh the blog posted I know how
difficult that is to stay on top of all
that stuff um absolutely yeah we've all
been there we have we all have been
there um it and okay so you've got the
next one so I'll go ahead and take this
one um this one is a Blog by suou and it
is a mongodb nosql injection sort of
technique um that he's releasing and
essentially it it's a describing a
scenario where you have a nosql
injection into a collection which is
like a table um in
nosql uh that is not really appreciate
you you translating this for nor because
even I I'm not like a like a mongod DB
offici a like I used I've used it maybe
like two or three times in the last 10
years like from a development
perspective and I rarely ever hack on it
so it's just one of those things that
you know having it in it's an edge case
you know technology and and um I I did
actually use mongodb for my uh Recon
system as my core database which was
like really not the right
choice and I discussed that for I will
say every time I've used it I have I
have somewhat regretted it like no squl
is is one of those things that um it's
really good for certain things I I would
say I think like you're doing o of one
type stuff where you know the key MH
then it's really quick for that like for
storing documents with like where you're
not trying to really filter where SQL
and like my SQL and like um you know
that relational yeah relational right
like those are much better for like
quering select star from blank where X
is Y and Z you know like that that type
of querying is so much better in
relational database and it is in a nosql
database would you say that relational
databases are better at
relationships they also have that
Advantage right like there is that whole
implicit thing with like linked like
foreign keys and all that kind of stuff
that I don't I don't think that exists
at all in um in
nosql and that does like it's not
necessary right like you can build those
relationships out yourself like you
store the same value in two fields or
whatever but again it like it has to go
through every single document because
it's not stored in that way so um yeah
it's definitely it's definitely a
different different approach and and it
definitely was not the right choice for
me from a was that the same reason why
you regret Yeah well yeah there because
at the end of the day you you
um when you're doing like Mass guilt
Recon you're going to be doing a ton of
writs and and not a lot of reads right
you you're just going to be writing
writing writing writing writing
constantly right um because you're going
to be updating all these rows every
second you know um and and
so that was one of the things that it's
just [__] doesn't scale super despite
mongod DV being web scale uh it doesn't
it doesn't do a bunch of Rights like
that um super well uh in my experience
and and there's lots of other stuff we
discussed it on the episode with Sean um
Sean yo from asset note I hope I'm
pronouncing his name right I don't I
wonder if people know what we're talking
about when we say mongod DV is web we've
definitely talked about it on the
podcast before but actually talked
talked about it in the Sha Yo episode
did we I believe we did I think so I'm
going to put a link I'm copying it right
now I'm putting a
link here's the video it's in the
description yeah it will actually be in
the description so go check that out um
or maybe just like put the graphic up on
the screen dude it it like opened up a
little card in in in the in the dock and
I just see that that character's face
and it just makes me laugh so much um
okay let me explain the freaking WR up
okay um so anyway now it's playing in
the background okay I so I'm sorry so
sirou uh mentions this this way to deal
with um nosql injection um and
essentially the the scenario is you're
in have a noqual injection in a public
collection so let's say for example a
products collection or something like
that I think was the one he used in the
in the write up um how can you pivot
this to affect other collections when
the collection is like sort of
statically defined and um the way that
he did this is he uses this this whole
feature of um mongodb called Aggregates
and Aggregates are ways to process these
multiple documents and uh run like
various computations on them get them
into a specific format filter them that
sort of thing there's two ways to do
this you can use aggregate pipelines or
you can use single purpose methods in
mongodb um and uh single purpose meth
methods are pretty single purpose and
not very useful for this aggregate
pipelines are are kind of the way to go
and essentially what that allows you to
do is use a bunch of different
functionality to um perform what would
be the equivalent of like a a union of
sorts um okay with other collections uh
uh in the database um I'm scrolling
through this blog as well and it looks
like there also is like an actual Union
thing that you can do as well is that
that's separate from this or no no no
that's same thing okay yeah so so um
there's multiple I I I don't actually
know the technical term for these uh
they
are essentially um dollar sign
operations I I don't know the technical
term for them but I'm I'm going to call
them functions for for lack of a better
um term here but there's dollar sign
lookup dollar sign Union WID dollar sign
replace WID and dollar sign merge and
those are the ones he highlights in the
um write up which essentially allow you
to do various uh operations within that
aggregate Pipeline and that pipeline is
is a an array of various uh operations
that you want to perform on uh the the
data the given data set so for example
if you use um dollar lookup it'll allow
you to look up a an object in a
different collection and attach that to
a specific field in the object that
you're you're querying and you can
combine that with limit so that you only
get one object back back so you can
query things very specifically um okay
so really quick so I did a little Google
search here so the aggregation thing
basically just takes a list of
operations that it's expecting to do in
order operations okay yeah and so
they're called aggregation operations
and there's a variety of them like match
group um you know what was it lookup um
Etc un with yeah all those okay that's
right I I I knew I had the name in there
somewhere aggregate operations that's
the one and um and so essentially the
whole concept here the takeaway if you
didn't listen to all that rambling and
jolen eyes back and forth is that if you
have a nosql ey um a nosql injection
then you should absolutely be looking
for uh ways to even if the The
Collection is limited you should be
looking for ways to use these aggregate
pipelines um to be able to reach into
other Collections and pull data out um
and he includes a really ful section in
the blog post called how to I identify
if it's an aggregate in blackbox testing
so essentially if your nosql um
injection includes the ability to have
Aggregates and essentially what he
mentions here is that you should always
look for anything that has like dollar
sign match or dollar sign lookup in it
or or that sort of thing um in built
into the application because that sort
of indicates the use of these aggregate
functionality and I've absolutely seen
these before in applications so I had
definitely missed something here um so
be on the lookout for those and then
also be on the lookout for an array that
seems to be providing some sort of
filtering because um this would be
pretty much where you would define an
aggregate pipeline um so if an API
request is taking in like a Json array
and there's some various um defining of
fields that are being pulled back or
like operations aggregate operations
like like Joel mentioned then that's
kind of the indicator of like okay maybe
I've got an aggregate um and no SQL C
that supports Aggregates here yeah and
it's one of those things that now that
that you know it you like like you said
like you you're thinking back and you're
like oh I've definitely seen some like
dollar sign weird stuff in those
requests like I probably missed some
stuff um make sure this is in your word
list too right so that you can you know
either hit some errors maybe you can you
know um as an exercise to the to the
listener go ahead and figure out some
sort of query or some sort of parameter
combination that will trigger an error
with these aggregates um you know call
so that you can put that in your word
list and you'll get a hit on your your
fuzzes uh when you're going through and
you'll know okay I need to poke it that
further that's probably you know a no
SQL injection yeah that's a great point
maybe there's some end points that sort
of aren't using this functionality in
the front end but may have it in the
back end and by fuzzing for parameters
inside the Json body or that sort of
thing you might like maybe an operation
that doesn't exist or something I don't
know yeah I I know that that nosql is
pretty Json heavy so I imagine you'll
find this mostly in in a Json
environment not to say that you won't
find it outside of that but um you know
this is probably something that you're
going to be brute forcing for in a in a
Json uh environment I am thinking about
all those all those like those grown
bugs like the the the show and tells typ
type stuff where it's going to be some
no SQL injection through like a URL form
encoded that nobody was anticipating
like yeah man yeah I always hesitate to
even say stuff like that on the Pod
sometimes because it's like okay clearly
this is true because of the way that
things work but also there's going to be
some caveat and I don't know maybe I
shouldn't even say it but no at the end
of the day it's better for us to do sort
of detection based hunting yeah yeah
yeah all right what's this next one we
got here okay so this is a really cool
blog post um that uh I don't know what
the
researchers name is other than stly St L
E1 123 um did they did they link any
socials uh not that I saw but I'll I'll
try to hunt it down oh they did actually
uh D Schmid
Schmid s c h m DT even not I'm sorry uh
dmid
um has like 75 followers make that 76
because I just I just followed them nice
um anyways so they did a a really cool
um blog post about a one-click account
takeover
in a very large chat app in South Korea
called caca chat um so if anybody's ever
been to Korea or um knows anybody in
Korea or friends in Korea or anything
like that you definitely know about this
app um kaca is like massive in Korea
they're like one of the largest sort of
like technology companies I'd say but
they're definitely more than just
technology they are in a lot of sectors
I think one thing that was really
interesting when I went to Korea was two
things one like the emphasis of um local
companies and local businesses so like
Google Maps barely works in Korea but
caca
Maps made by the same company uh works
great right and so um uh you know most
of the cars that people Drive South
Korean uh manufacturers Hyundai Kia that
kind of stuff um you don't see that to
the same level at all in the US like
people aren't like exclusively driving
American cars we drive tons of import
cars you see Toyotas and Nissan
everywhere um so it's uh it's very
interesting the emphasis that I noticed
in Korea on like I've been waiting for
my moment to now derail you good sir
since you derailed me during the
nol
okay I I got kind of nerd sniped by this
because this is this is I I pulled a
Joel moment here okay so I I was reading
about this and I I didn't actually get
but like a you know a little bit into
the blog so I'm going to rely on you to
explain uh most of everything that
happened here but I got like 2 seconds
into it and it was like oh caca talk the
biggest uh app you know in Korea and I
was like wait a second isn't lion Korean
because I lived in Japan and everyone in
Japan uses line like like it seems line
is also pretty big over there yeah and
and so I was like oh wait okay let me
let me sus this out and it actually
looks like Lon is actually gaining
popularity in in Korea now um but kaca
is by far the the leader there which is
which is pretty cool I have Kaka talk on
my phone because I have a friend who
lives in Korea and that's talk them wow
that's that's pretty rad yeah and same
same for L you know I use that for all
my Japanese friends um but it made me
also sort of think like as far as like
all these different countries go they
all have their all in one app right line
does payments caca talk does payments
you said Maps you know there's the all
in one app for that country right um
China has like what is it like WeChat or
something like that yeah and so the US
doesn't have one of those and I think
Europe kind of does like we chat or some
or or what is it um WhatsApp WhatsApp
yeah primarily WhatsApp so I I think it
it's mostly a cultural thing um a
cultural thing combined with
um probably a lot of like smaller
factors like you know economic factors
and and stuff but in the US you see
primarily people either text yeah right
it's either text or it's iMessage and
then if it's not it's one of the apps
that the rest of the world also uses
telegram signal WhatsApp or maybe one of
the more Niche ones there are a couple
like Facebook Messenger right like
Facebook Messenger let's so like line
like you'll almost never see somebody in
the US using it unless they're talking
to somebody in Asia right um so it's
it's kind of it's kind of interesting
that the US never like really adopted
like a single chat app but I think
that's primarily because iMessage is
very very popular here and one of the
things that was pushed at least in in my
memory is that iMessage works over data
so it doesn't take International charges
or anything like that it works over
Wi-Fi so if you're on Wi-Fi or or you
have you know internet connectivity it's
not using like your SM like you know use
pay per message and all that kind of
stuff and yeah right so um I think that
was a big reason why people were using
Whatsapp in other countries was so that
they could chat you know cross country
without international texting fees and
all that kind of stuff especially with
SMS yeah and with the US just being as
huge as it is I think the issue isn't
there quite as much but I also made me
think like this is something that I've
heard Elon Musk talk about a little bit
with X is that he kind of wants it to be
the all-in-one app for the US you know
have payments have chatting have social
media that sort of thing and um you know
I don't know if he's going to pull it
off it doesn't seem like it at least the
we they haven't moved towards that
direction uh very substantially in the
time that he's been running it but um
the vision is there right you know the
that model is validated in lots of other
countries um so it just kind of made me
think like hm X's seems to be the only
one that is actually really aggressively
going after that so maybe it'll happen
yeah yeah maybe it will happen I don't
know it's interesting I I still find
myself feeling that Twitter is in like a
extremely Niche
and becoming more Niche social network
where
like the people who do use it are
already like at a certain point in terms
of like social connectivity like you
know
random you know Boomer is probably not
like going and signing up for Twitter
today you know what I mean like maybe
they are but I think it's more like
younger people who are like hooked into
social media already who are signing up
as like Twitter users more than like
people are like H let's see what's on
Twitter today you know what I mean like
but maybe I'm wrong about that I don't
know yeah I don't know they definitely
take more research um but I I think I
think just the fact that X has that
vision is pretty cool um so I don't know
we'll see where it takes it I'm I'm a
big fan of x i I use it pretty regularly
it's my top social media get a lot of
the the stuff that we talk about on the
podcast from X so um yeah I don't could
be cool all right sorry back to back to
your bug anyways anyways okay so caca
caca is um you know very uh large um
software company company in general in
Korea um K chat very large probably the
the most popular chat app in South Korea
um so there was a really interesting
chain of bugs that this researcher found
so essentially it it started out with
the fact that there was a deep link that
could be used to
open um somewhat arbitrary URLs and it
had JavaScript enabled um so that's
always interesting because JavaScript
enabled means that you can potentially
do an excess you have an xss so there
are a couple different attack vectors
mainly you know JavaScript interfaces or
potentially redirecting the user to an
arbitrary your a but even then you kind
of need to chain that with something
else um and uh there was a other
interesting things that they had noticed
like that you could use in tenu eyes
which I don't think is enabled by
default so that is a little odd um and I
don't actually think that they ended up
using that so it was it was interesting
they they called it out uh but I don't
think it was part of the final exploit
uh but it is pretty interesting uh thing
to check for just to see if it's you
know possible because as they as I noted
it would allow you to interact with
non-exported um parts of the app um um
via JavaScript through like you know
redirecting them to URL so it's it's an
interesting attack Vector um but
basically what they found is that if you
hit this specific uh URL scheme it would
open a u like a set URL with like
something following the path um and so
they tested a bunch of things and one
other thing that they noticed was that
you could leak the off token to
basically any URL with something so it's
it's like one of those um short URLs or
or one of those so like
example host and then that would take
you to like example.com host blank okay
okay so it's allowing you to open up in
the web view it's allowing you to
control somewhat what what is being
opened up in the web view right right
somewhat yeah so pretty interesting um
and uh so they were like all right well
we have JavaScript functionality and we
have this
you know somewhat controllable URL like
let's see if we can do this and there
was a check function that they look
through and basically it was strict
enough that they couldn't really find
some way to like bypass the parsing so
they would have to do essentially a
secondary vulnerability like an open
redirect or something like that um so
sure enough they
find an open redirect uh on this
subdomain specifically so um the the way
that this worked was the it would
actually take them to a subdomain with
like a clean path so that the path
wasn't set on the URL was just taking
them to a specific subdomain with like
arbitrary path um so they found a path
underneath this host that would allow
them to do an uh an open redirect to
any any other host within that root
domain okay so this is like the semi
closed redirect that we were talking
about I don't need to to talk so oated
here because it's all on the blog post
so let me let me try and clear it up so
basically kaca talk
Colby takes you to BU thea.com
path right um and then they found an
open to redirect under buy. ca.com that
would take them to any ca.com
URL allow them to read to any you know
subdomain under.com right yeah so then
they search even further like okay so we
can hit this deep link we can use the
open redirect on that subdomain to now
go to any URL within the root
domain how do we escalate this um and
and one thing I mentioned U I don't know
if I fully got through it but they
noticed that the off token gets set on
every request so it doesn't matter if
they're specifically going to a caca
domain in that web view if they request
to any host including an attacker
control
URL that off can get sent as a header
dude this is this is something that I
see fairly often in a mobile environment
I wonder why that is do do you know why
they like it's just some like when I
think about it from like a web
perspective I'm like okay there's like
some sort of service worker sitting in
place there just adding the off header
to every single request is that
something you see pretty often in Mobile
like yeah so one of the one of the
things I um I actually covered this a
little bit in the recent SSL um
unpinning master class that I did but um
retrofit is a very popular
um Android uh like request library and I
think it's a good good example for this
because it has this concept of
interceptors and basically an
Interceptor runs on every single request
that goes through the request Factory
and it'll you know add headers check
various things whatever add off all that
kind of stuff so what's my guess is what
H is happening is that they just have a
generic Interceptor that adds off to
every single request because the
assumption is it's never going to be
possible to hit any URL that's attacking
controlled so it's not even like on
their radar but all it takes is you know
some crafty you know work here and you
know now now you can figure out how to
get right because they weren't expecting
oh there's an open redirect somewhere
else on this on this sub domain right um
so with that open redirect they can get
to any roou domain they keep digging
they do some Google Dorking and they
find I found this very interesting they
found a Dom Invader Canary that was like
ased by
Google and they're like oh that looks
like that looks like a Dom Invader uh
Canary so they it ended up being an
xss it's like a Dom XS like a or like a
stored xss um that like popped an alert
and they're like okay actually I think
it might well I guess it's a Dom EXs I
think it's yeah they call it a store but
I think it's stomach um anyways so they
they keep digging they keep digging they
find another endpoint um where this you
know search parameter whatever is
getting passed in and they get uh you
know another Dom xss basically so they
they find a bypass on a different
endpoint and get a functional uh Dom xss
on this separate subdomain um it's what
is it m. shopping how. cow.com
um so now they have an xss on a
different subdomain and they have a way
to redirect to that subdomain and they
have a way to open that redirect through
a deep bling so what the what you would
do is like you know as as an attacker
like or the victim or whatever like you
send them a link through the chat and
they click on that link and that
link
uh is a deep link that opens the byy you
know caca talk
pby that redirects everything after that
to the open redirect which then triggers
the open redirect goes to a different
subdomain which pops the
xss which then open uses that JavaScript
execution to send them to an attacker
controlled URL which then loads the
attacker controlled page with your off
token being sent automatically and now
the attacker has your your off it's
oneck at wow dude that is quite a flow
so deep link to open redirect to xss
which is essentially just a client Side
open redirect in this scenario um and
then which is fine because JavaScript is
set to enable in the web View and then
uh then it it redirects to an attacker
control domain which is where that that
piece you mentioned where the offhe
header gets added to every request comes
in and you just snag the victim's off
token it's basically like a limited
redirect to to an open redirect to an
atto because the first one only lets you
go to domains Within ca.com
but then by pivoting that to an xss you
use the xss to actually just set set the
target Ura like they're literally just
setting document do location yeah
exactly so it's not like anything crazy
um they're just sending them to the
attacker control URL because the attack
Vector is that the token gets set as
like a header automatically so all they
need to do is load the URL dude that's
that's pretty freaking sick this is a
great this is a great example of a
mobile attack chain
yeah well I was going to say like you
know a lot of the times like you know
you get very caught up in like the Weeds
on like um you know trying to find a
JavaScript interface or something but
sometimes it's the very simple Behavior
like this like setting the off token on
every request and one thing I liked is
that they included a way for you to test
this um where well Mo most of the way to
test this I have a I have a little free
to gadget that I love that I use all the
time that globally sets all web views to
be debuggable
um and if I notice that something as a
web view one of the first things I do is
I run that script so that I can use the
Chrome inspect Tool uh to attach to it
and check stuff like this like one of
the things you can do is you can
literally just open the console in the
Chrome inspect uh on the device and you
do document allocation equals you know
attacker url.com and then you check the
request and you see did it send a token
anywhere and if you did then you go okay
now you're looking for open redirects
you're looking for arbitrary URL you
know or like arbitrary URL uh opens like
that kind of stuff because all you need
to do is load one attacker control page
and it's it's ATL the the another
takeaway for me here is that any deep
link that results that interacts with a
web view or controls the destination
that a web view will be sent to is
extremely interesting and should be very
thoroughly vetted because anytime you
can control that sort of thing once
again we're just weaponizing redirects
and we're getting Gadgets in our pocket
that we can use in full attack chains
and and I think I think we mentioned
this last episode or the episode before
but um I think there's a lot to be said
for going and finding the gadget that
you need like I I think often times as
we start looking for gadgets there's
like a couple levels of that and it's
like oh you identify a gadget great I'll
have it in my pocket and I'll use it
whenever I I find you know just happen
to stumble upon the other piece that I
need but then the next level is like
okay I've got this gadget how can I
force this gadget to work right and and
you go and you find the open redirect
you you don't just give up on this on
the closed redirect or whatever that
that uh or semi-open redirect that they
found that allowed them to get to a
different um domain uh subdomain within
the same uh top level domain and you you
push it further and further and further
till you find the xss and pop the full
attack chain really really good write up
I like this a lot yeah yeah absolutely
um I I totally agree I think it's one of
those really good cases that
shows um that you don't NE you don't
like full mobile skills like to to find
like a really impactful mobile bug like
a lot of the times it relies on stuff
like this like open redirects and and
just like standard xss to get that full
attack vector and it doesn't need to be
anything crazy like oh like all the
stars have to align to open a arbitrary
URL like all you need is some web view
that has JavaScript um execution in some
way to uh even get like partial control
of that URL or get JavaScript execution
within there like like um you know
opening it to like a product page that
has an excess payload or something like
you know there there's a lot of
different ways where this can manifest
so um you know just thinking creatively
and outside of the box and having those
gadgets in your brain uh will let you
let you get there it's another it's
another thing as well it's another
reason that you should try to expand
your abilities as a hacker you shouldn't
just stay in your lane right because
marginal mobile skills like like I I
have very confident that I could have
found this bug if I was looking at this
app right um because all it takes is
knowledge of deep links and with that's
something we covered in our mobile
episodes back on like episode eight or
something like that and uh it's stuck in
my head ever since and then everything
after that is essentially just uh web
hacking um so just just a little bit of
knowledge in your target area combined
with your current expertise can really
allow you to to pop some very impactful
bugs so um I will say one last comment
that I had on this
as you talking through it I was reading
uh through the the blog it says we
reported this vulnerability in December
2023 to kow's uh bug Bounty program
however we didn't receive any reward as
only Koreans are eligible to receive a
bounty which is like so messed up dude
it's it's it's very interesting I have a
feeling there's some weird um there's
some weird Financial regulations or who
knows what yeah it's um that is that is
kind of unfortunate but but um maybe
maybe you can find a friend at Korea who
yeah exactly just DM it to your Korean
friend hey man you want want 500 bucks
yeah it's a good time to make friends in
Korea exactly exactly and I think
actually we were trying to find someone
mentioned in the in the critical
thinking Discord was like hey is anyone
here Korean you know because it's like I
need someone from Korea to do something
and like okay that's great I dig it um
all right dude once again we are 30
minutes in and still on the second news
item so I'm going to Breeze through this
next one pretty quickly um this next one
is a um a write up on essentially secret
based um or or time-based Secrets uh and
being used for various uh different
things like password resets and and that
sort of thing um it's called reset
tolken which is just an absolutely
amazing name uh one token to rule them
all uh a play on um on Jr tolken um Jr
no I'm kind of J yes yeah JRR token
that's I I forgot Nar I was like wait a
second do I know things about uh
literature do I know things about
anything besides hacking um uh yeah so
cool cool name cool write up I I dig it
I'm intrigued I'll I'll click you know
I'll click uh and essentially I read
through it it's pretty long um the the
author does a really good um job of sort
of addressing the methodology used
throughout this whole research um so I'm
going to condense it down to top tips
and tldrs for you here uh and
essentially those are that you should be
on the lookout for anything that uses
php's unique ID function I think we
mentioned this in the PHP episodes as
well
um that is uh not secure and generated
based off of the current time and date
and also mongodb's object ID uh is also
not secure and is based off of a
timestamp a process ID and a counter
um so that that can also be uh uh
guessed with a a decent amount of
accuracy um and the other tip that I had
in here uh that was just kind of in this
nice little blue tip box which was
awesome which is anytime you're doing
any sort of time-based attacks um
against a a server there is this
mandatory header that must be returned
with every single request called Date um
and that is the current server time uh
and so that is really helpful if you're
trying to figure out okay what time does
the server think it is if they're
generating these sort of um uh time
based tokens and so you can use that
date header uh to perform various
operations and that's exactly what the
author does they create this tool called
um uh I think it's called reset token
yeah it is it's called reset token and
essentially it does something that I've
actually had success with in the past
which is uh it takes the current date
from the server which is which is
awesome using that that date header you
just copy and paste the date header into
the tool and you give it uh a token and
you give it some data about your account
like your email that sort of thing and
it will try um six different formats uh
with a bunch of different hashes a bunch
of different um uh flows to see if they
can get a a collision with the hash that
you provided so let's say you do a
password reset you get the date on on
that you pass it to the thing you give
it the password reset token you give it
your email and it's just going to Brute
Force you know milliseconds backwards
milliseconds forwards uh you know Shaw
one Shaw 256 uh you know timestamp plus
your email sha 256 concatenate you know
and then shortened you know all these
different combinations to see if he can
get a collision and um I just wanted to
shout out that because I think that's
awesome and I would love to see some
more Community contributions to uh the
the structures that they have in there
because there's only six currently and I
think they're pretty good but there
there's only
um and I also wanted to say that I've
talked about this on the podcast before
but I have found this bug this was one
of the first bugs that I ever one of the
first criticals I ever submitted um was
a password reset token that was being
generated by
md5 uh of the user's email plus the
current Unix timestamp and I just
guessed that [__] dude I guessed it I
looked at that I did I guessed it and I
was like and I was like man I feel like
that's an md5 hash and I feel like
they're just doing email plus and is
just like one of those scenarios of just
crazy no it was like some serious
psychic [__] happening here like ve very
kind of crazy and on that one time I
wrote The Python script to generate it
and somehow it actually worked on that
same Target and um and so they are out
there they are out there for sure uh so
I'm I was excited to see this actually
put into practice and I think this could
make a really good kaido extension or
burp extension where um able to select a
a tool or like um a specific token and
pass it to the tool and see if there any
results come back I think that'd be
pretty awesome yeah yeah absolutely
that's uh that's really crazy yeah
that's uh that's such a good tip yeah
and I think I think also just regarding
this um James Kettle will also be James
Kettle retweeted this which is why it
kind of popped into my feed and I think
he's doing some timing based stuff uh
and I wouldn't be surprised if he also
uses this really cool tip with the date
being in the response um header and and
um using that to do some other time
based attacks yeah I will say like I
feel like there's a bunch of attacks
that probably 10 years ago 15 years ago
would have been like theoretically this
is possible but we don't really at scale
it would take too long now we
have very powerful computers and Ai and
all sorts of fancy things that can
optimize these problems and make them
more solvable and um we're starting to
see like actual poc's for these things
coming out now um and so all the old
systems that are stuck around that uh
we're like well that'll never be
exploited it's what is it it's it's RSA
like it'll be
fine and so now uh here we are so it's
uh it's really interesting to see this
type of research and I'm excited to see
uh more of this kind of stuff yeah yeah
same man it it's definitely yeah scary
to see where all that stuff will go um
all right you want to do the iOS uh the
next iOS one or should I talk about the
uh Jingo one yeah so I'm gonna I'm G to
try this iOS one because it's uh it it's
kind of complicated to understand um and
and I've I've sat here like reading
through it a couple times and I'm just
like you know uh I don't know it's still
a little bit confusing to me so I'd
recommend that you go and read through
it but my understanding is that
essentially um if you you've probably
seen it well you don't have an iPhone
but uh if you have an iPhone you've
probably seen this thing where um you go
to sign in to I don't know like with
Google or something it's some app and
you click that and it opens up a web
View and it says you
know XX would like to sign in would
would like to use google.com to sign in
and it will like open this URL and it'll
do this whole sign in process um and so
uh there's some you know Miss checks on
the back end when there's multiple apps
that register the same off uh like URL
like redirect scheme basically with the
with the authenticated web view like
popup thing and so you can use an
attacker domain to redirect to that URL
it will go through the normal off flow
like if they have a session there it'll
like say yep and then you can also use
prompt equals
none um which was I guess the the big
like key to make this work to allow it
to uh essentially skip through any sort
of user confirmation or verification or
anything like that so it just like opens
verifies skips right through sends the
code to the attacker domain and then
continues on um so it's h it was super
super interesting I don't actually know
what the fix was because they said that
in the mitigation they go app store
review is not a mitigation here um so I
don't know if there is an actual
mitigation that mation that they
mentioned was instead of using um some
of these other uh links I forget what
the other ones are called that are just
the domain name reversed instead use
Universal links uh so the quote here
would be apple offers Universal links
that are not hijack meaning an attacker
would not be able to retrieve the uh
redirect with the authentication code um
there you go so that's the redirect I
will sounds a little bit more like the
Android flow yeah and I will add a
couple things to this because I I did
get the chance to go through this one so
um custom URL schemes that's the thing
that that you're you're not supposed to
use um for for this that that are hijack
like you said they apps can register
multiple diff like multiple different
apps can register these um and I think
there was a a fix put into place for
that but essentially what they what they
did now is using this as web
authentication session um feature uh to
authenticate using the cookies that are
active inside of the Safari app inside
of your app instead of your malicious
app um is what I I think triggered this
whole thing and essentially when you use
that as web authentication session thing
it will pop open that little that little
uh prompt that you mentioned that I have
never seen because I never use an
iPhone um and and then but it'll say
like hey you know we're trying to
authenticate with like um this is Evan
connell's write up uh in in conjunction
with um Julian Mr Tux racer um and so
the the screenshot that he has there is
like you know oathy wants to use evanc
connell.com to sign in and the user
would say okay sure but then as soon as
you open evanc connell.com
that that uh you can just redirect since
you control that domain you can just
redirect to like google.com and do the
prompt none like you said and the the
when the call back happens it'll
automatically go back to your app that
triggered that that start so it requires
you to have a malicious app on the
device and then it requires you to set
up this sort of redirect inside of this
web view um that is defined via this as
web authentication session functionality
um and that allows you to hijack the the
code when it comes back which can be
used to do account Takeover in a ton of
different environments so I think they
said like 30 apps or something were
vulnerable to this and uh because
they're not using the universal links
instead they're using the the custom um
URL scheme yeah and I want to say there
was an interesting discussion I saw on
Twitter somewhere where either it was
from Evan Connelly or Evan had chimed in
or something that was discussing um the
severity evaluations of mobile app uh
bugs especially ones that require uh an
app to be on the device um and that's
always definitely like a tricky scenario
because and again uh we've talked about
this we talked about this a couple
episodes actually or last episode or so
where you know it'd be really
interesting to see some data from people
like Google and apple somebody post did
you see that did they yeah did they find
the data I think it was in the critical
thinking Discord or maybe it was Twitter
or something I I I don't remember
exactly where it was but someone heard
you say that in the past episode and
track down like uh some data on that
that somebody had released uh I should
have saved it and sent it to you I
thought you would have seen it um but
essentially it's pretty common that that
that was the essentially the tldr that
was attached to that comment was yeah it
happens all the time that that a
malicious app is actually on a user's
device so um I think oh yeah here it is
from Evan yeah and it's a link from
Facebook on latest pod you said you were
interested in research on the frequency
of malicious mobile apps making through
App Store review this is something I
came across used to make our case when
we needed uh with the iOS ooth uh
account takeover attack in short it
seems to happen fairly often and then
there's a quote from this uh this is a
um a post uh from meta's own blog uh in
October of 2022 that says our security
researchers have found more than 400
malicious Android and iOS apps this year
in 2022 that were designed to steal
Facebook login information and
compromise people's accounts these apps
were listed on the Play Store and
Apple's App Store and disguises photo
editors games VPN Services business apps
and other utilities to trick other
people into downloading them so 400 mil
did I say 400
million 400 malicious yeah okay yeah 400
malicious Android so that's across
Android and iOS
400 it sounds like a lot uh but um when
you think about how many apps there are
it's like you know there's probably
actually millions of apps right so
that's only that's only focused towards
attacking meta right so so that's that's
kind of interesting and and I think
which like one of the top five largest
companies in the world but yes yeah like
I will say like it it it for sure
happens right like and if there's going
to be a Target it's going to be Facebook
Google Twitter like probably right like
those are like at least Facebook and
Google are going to be so an apple
probably are going to be like your top
three like Target Microsoft right
totally agre um so but uh that being
said I I think I'd like to see what that
means like 400 again like sounds like a
lot I'm not saying 400's not a lot um
but I would be really curious to know
like an install count or something right
like how many like okay like how many
yeah what's the install count for that
now compare that to the total install
counts of all the apps during 2022 what
percentage of installs were malicious
apps yeah what percentage ofes have had
aous app installed on them in the past
three years or something like that right
yeah exactly and like I know these are
really hard things to quantify so I'm
not expecting anybody to have an answer
um but that's I think what especially
from from like a program perspective
like if that article works and that
numbers like if that's what you need to
prove it like rock on but um I I from
like the program side would be really
interested for like the threat
evaluation to see some like in
perspective statistics again on like
what that means and what that looks like
in like the overall picture and like
what the risk is uh as a whole yeah I
totally agree I I think that would be
really interesting area um one one last
thing I wanted to mention on this this
super cool iOS uh AWA thing um one of
course the prompt none super helpful
please keep that in your brains prompt
nun works on so many different o um
implementations uh of course the
prerequisite of that is that the user
has to already have authorized a certain
application or whatever um but was it
prop none in the a thing that we talked
about last week as well or was that
separate I don't remember we'll have to
go back and check um but the the last
thing that I wanted to mention was that
this this so you mentioned being able to
multiple apps being able to register the
same scheme and in Android if I
understand if I remember correctly it
like if it's trying to redirect back
it'll prompt you to select the app that
has preced in to to have um the call
back for this specific Uh custom scheme
or whatever um and it it mentions in
here that with the as web authenticated
session piece the reason why doesn't do
that is it's because whichever app
originated that off flow inside of the
web view will get the call back uh if
they have that scheme registered without
any any sort of prompting or any sort of
other
reprioritization um so that's another
that's another one of the problems with
that whole flow is like that's not great
um so hopefully Apple will will go ahead
and get this get this fixed if not in
the meantime you know I imagine Mr Tux
racer and Evan Connelly have kind of
cleaned this up across uh various bug
bounding programs um and and I did I
think they were discussing it in the
critical thinking Discord um I think
they said that this was most of the time
accepted as a high and uh and there
there were some scenarios where it was
dropped to a medium or a low but of
those you know 30 probably at least 20
accepted it as a high which I think is
pretty rad um and kind of speaks to the
the impact of doing this sort of larger
scale research on applications that can
be applied across the board so very very
cool work there for sure yeah um so real
quick I did go find the link uh from
last episode it was um specifically it
was um the zoom account takeover bug um
and it was not the same thing it was the
fact that you could set response type to
code comma ID token to multiple values
so I think I would love to see some
research on this but even
uh if you don't decide to publish it I
think it it would be a very worthwhile
time investment to go take a look at oo
take a look at the open uh ID ooth
implementation available parameters take
a look at the spec take a look at where
it's possible to send multiple values
where it's possible to send values that
are optional um and either write some
tooling or add into your testing flow to
be testing for these things like prompt
none sending multiple things to response
type um sending you know uh what is it
um client
uh the the response token is that what
you're talking about uh yeah ID
credentials um as the uh as the token
type or whatever um you know there's a
lot of different things that you can
test here um and I think it's uh it
seems to be a really ripe area for
research yeah yeah I agree and I I will
say I now that you mentioned that I I
did go back and look at the zoom right
up and they actually do say that just
not very explicit licitly they say quote
meanwhile in window B the oo flow takes
place as we have modified The Prompt
parameter to no longer ask the user to
select an account everything will happen
automatically and if you look at the
exploit code they're using um prompt
none for that uh in in the at the very
end of the window B's location sort of
piece there um so yeah I think I think
that is a a killer tip the prompt none
and then um this this additional
additional piece uh about understanding
the mechanics surrounding
um how oath is implemented inside of a
iOS application I think iOS applications
are a little bit tricky too A lot of
people can do more Android stuff than
iOS so Props to them for going after iOS
stuff yeah yeah totally um all right so
I'm gonna hop over to um another write
up that will be the last one for our
news section today um and that is uh
some research that just came out I want
to say yesterday or day before yesterday
um on OMS uh and this research is done
by Elam um more specifically Alex Brown
um I've seen a lot of cool stuff come
out of Elam so that's pretty rad um and
this whole concept of uh object uh
relational mappers or ORS are often
found in crms um such as Jango and that
sort of thing um and essentially they
are layers of extraction on top of the
database so that you can connect your
various dat Oh Yeah from the Developers
so like yeah like anytime I'm doing any
work with the database I'm always using
an RM um you know it's basically just
like you create a class and you say like
here's the fields here's the type of
those fields and then through magic omms
it does all that in the database and it
creates those relationships between
classes and objects that you can just be
like get me 50 of this and it'll be like
here's a class with all the attributes
and everything that are set to these
field values that are and it's all
stored in the database and it all
there's for the foreign Keys work and
all that kind of stuff so it just makes
working with databases really nice it
does but it also adds another layer of
abstraction and extraction is is
dangerous uh because you don't exactly
understand what's happening at the lower
level sometimes especially if you're you
know more Junior developer something
like that um so the the tldr of this
write up and you should absolutely go
read it because I think this applies to
a lot of different um Frameworks and and
structures uh OMS as Joel mentioned is
are pretty popular sort of uh
abstraction on top of the database um so
I could definitely see this happening in
other different areas and the writer
here um the author of this this write up
uh describes a couple scenarios where
it's like okay you know now we need to
be able to filter on various Fields
inside this thing and they keep on
changing the fields so now we're just
going to make it filterable on every
field and um essentially What's
Happening Here is if if if there is a
situation which there was in jeno om
where uh you're able to supply apply a
specific um a Json blob which then gets
passed directly into the filter piece of
this omm you may be able to uh specify
filter chains of sorts um essentially
supplying arbitrary parameters to this
filter function and as like this is a
common theme that I've seen across a lot
of different exploits is like any
scenario where you are able as the user
to provide arbitrary parameters
uh like um keyword parameters uh call
arbitrary functions with no defined
parameter you know that sort of thing
like we saw with the indirect object
invocation um from the GitHub Enterprise
or um the name of the game nowadays is
parameter testing parameter fuzzing yeah
like finding those uh those things that
the developers are using behind the
scenes uh that are sent in internal API
requests and um weren't supposed to be
seen by the public yeah absolutely and
and this this whole thing kind of
reminds me of the reflection or uh
indirect method thing that we discussed
with the GitHub Enterprise bug um but
essentially what it's allowing you to do
here is filter off of any um any field
and what it will allow you to do then is
provide things like password uncore
uncore starts with where underscore
uncore is a specific filter or selector
on on that field um and then the the
author also shows how so obviously using
that if it provides any response if you
can get it to do like a true or false
response um even if it's not returning
that password you can determine what
that character is um line you know um by
by just brute forcing all the the
possible character space uh line by line
H or character by character and um the
exploit that they wrote is really really
beautiful so definitely check out the
write up and look at those gifts on
seeing a password has just appear on
your screen one character at a time it's
just super like you know hacker porn
essentially there um uh but the the
write up was really good and it also
shows how you can chain these so so how
in Jingo RM you're able to to say like
okay for every article um the article
that was created by and that that
references to like the user object and
then you can select the user's password
and then underscore uncore contains or
like underscore uncore starts with or
whatever the set of filters that they
have um can be applied to these fields
which can allow you to leak the the
output character by character um and
then one last thing on this was was that
uh
even if you don't have something that
provides like sort of a Boolean output
uh whether you have a match or not um
the author was able to utilize uh Rex um
Doss essentially to tell you whether you
have select successfully selected a
character so you'll instead of defining
you know underscore uncore contains you
have some sort of reject that's in place
that when it matches it will cause a
reject dos which will stall the system
until you have the correct character
yeah it's such a it's such a creative
way of like basically doing like a sleep
uh or like a sleep based or air based uh
like injection uh where it's basically
you're doing a uh like a a look behind
or a look ahead um and then you after
that you're doing like a really
intensive Rex that's going to take a lot
of time or it's going to time out and so
if it matches and like proceeds then
it's going to you know error and if it
you know just really quickly then it's
not in a match exactly exactly so um I
think this is a really cool technique
that I've seen used by super Elite
hackers in a lot of contexts is this
sort of character bych character um
exfiltration and even usage of
error-based um implementations of this
sort of thing so uh definitely kind of
have that in your brain as you're
thinking about um the structures of some
of these apis and if there is any
functionality that allows you to search
or like provide specific characters or
like reject something um you often see
these used in in cross-site leaks as
well um definitely be on the lookout for
these uh is the big takeaway uh for me
yeah yeah
totally um all right uh let me see I'm
going to take a look at the notes really
quickly here yeah I the only other thing
that I had here is like this sort of
makes me think of graphql related stuff
on how they're hopping from object to
object within the database um and this
om mapping sort of allows you to do that
so um any scenarios you know we see that
in graphql all the time where it's like
okay you know I can't access this user
object directly but if I go through like
the article and then created by and then
author and then user then I can access
this so any any type of times where you
can do chains of um various object
relationships I think that area is sort
of ripe for vulnerabilities because the
complexity goes way up from the on the
development side and it it's hard to
sort of think of all those scenarios
yeah yeah totally totally um all right
so that's the news and now we're in um
and and now we're going to go ahead and
move to a uh Community bug submission um
and for those of you that aren't aware
of this essentially we offer to the
critical thinkers tier on Discord um the
ability to submit a bug that they might
want to have featured on the podcast and
uh if that bug is selected then we're
going to go ahead and air it on the
podcast and sort of discuss it as well
um and very apt for uh today's uh
podcast this uh Community bug submission
is by Evan Connelly the same guy that
did the iOS ooth right up so uh congrats
for absolutely crushing it lately Evan
you've been rocking it um and we'll go
ahead and jump into that uh that
explanation of the bug by him now hey
everyone my name is Evan and this is my
first bug mounty bug so back in 2019 I
just gotten a Tesla Model 3 and I came
across the fact they had a bug Bounty
program where you could register the
vehicle and they'd pay for findings and
so that just seemed so cool to me and
for whatever reason I just became a goal
of mine that I was going to find a bug
not just in their program but
specifically with the vehicle and so
this led to a deep dive I was going
through all the diagrams for the
electrical diagrams and schematics all
that kind of stuff and I just needed to
understand how does this thing work what
are all these different components
what's this do and end up spent a whole
lot of time looking at the diagnostic
ethernet port so that was readily
accessible within the cabin you could
plug a laptop in and it just seemed like
a good way to get in but banging my head
against a whole lot because it was
locked down pretty well with a firewall
and there really wasn't a whole lot of
interesting traffic you couldn't really
reach anything do anything interesting
there but I was determined I am going to
find a bug and so it's like this
stubborn determination of I don't care
how unlikely seems I don't care how
unqualified I feel like I might be to
actually do this I am going to find a
bug and I'll just keep trying until I do
and so at some point it occurred to me
maybe I should try to look at the same
port in different states like
specifically a software update what
would happen if I'm plugged in during a
software update maybe like momentarily
I'll see something interesting or
something reboots or something like that
and so I tried that I sat in the car for
like a half hour during a software
update and honestly I end up just seeing
less activity but then at the end of
that software update I'm plugged in and
all of a sudden I've got wire shark open
and it just starts it explodes like I'm
seeing packet after packet after packet
and so I get that feeling we all know
when you find something cool it's like
your heart skips a beat and you're like
I did it and um start looking through
all that there's HTTP traffic from
different hosts within the car it just
seems like there's a whole lot of
potential here and you know part of me
is immediately like all right well I now
I need to report this but I forced
myself to slow down did some more
research I believe over a few days and I
was able to understand a whole lot more
about these different hosts within the
car what they do some of the
unauthenticated API end points and there
was one where you could actually
download all the configuration values
from the infotainment system and so I'm
looking through all these different
parameters and I also found one where
you could change these values and so as
I'm doing all that I come across one in
particular that's super interesting it
was remote start and so I try it and
sure enough you can set remote start to
true and so with that I try it and now
there's a pop up on the infotainment
system I can see that remote start has
occurred and I end up testing this a few
more times with no key present it turns
out through this method there was a
24-hour period after any software update
where you could digitally hotwire a
Tesla you could plug a laptop in I even
demonstrated it with an iPad and just
through hitting an unauthenticated API
endpoint you could Hotwire that car and
drive off with no key card present and
so uh with that then I had this really
cool way of presenting it to Tesla I got
that report in and come to find out um
you know as everyone does as I still do
looking at that Bounty table expecting
full Bounty they come back to me and
they gave me I believe $3,500 but the
reasoning was it was a dupe but despite
being a dupe they paid it out anyway
because of the impact that I showed and
so lessons there have stuck with me I
think even help with web apps could
maybe help with somebody else first off
is just that Persistence of I'm going to
bang my head against the wall I don't
care how many times I have to try I'm
going to keep trying until I find
something and with that checking all
those different states you know does
this change if it's in this state or
that state I think that applies a whole
lot to web apps as well and then also
showing Max impact I think I'm going to
slow down I'm going to see what I can do
with this going to see if I can escalate
this but presenting this in a way that's
super compelling for the program those
are two things I've tried to apply ever
since I think they've helped me a whole
lot and so I just hope they helped
someone else as well but uh that's my
story there thanks for listening dang
dude what a freaking bug that was cool
the whole time I was listening as soon
as he was like oh there's this physical
ethernet port I'm I'm thinking oh no
yeah like I know where this is going um
because it's such a it's such a hard um
you know like I think with something
like a car it's a little bit of a
different attack Vector um because
there's like it's like one of the it's
like a physical thing where like you
know you can just like bust a window and
the hot wire aspect is is a really
strong attack scenario but if we're
anything else um than like remote start
or something like you know maliciously
like you know intercept like doing
something during the software update or
anything like that like the for sure
that would have been like not mitigating
factor and the other fun thing was when
he was like uh that that it got Clos as
a
dupe um I have only ever reported one
bug to Tesla
no with Sam Curry and it was not the
same bug but it wasn't also a dupe and
it ended up being that uh you know Sam
like picked me up uh at the airport uh
in his Tesla and I was just like
fiddling with the back and like uh
immediately like found something and so
we reported it and then like uh a little
while later we here back and they're
like hey uh this is actually fixed in
the latest update um make sure that your
car is up to date but sure enough we had
to go out and update the car Sam hadn't
done a software update on his car Sam
hadn't done a software update which is
good because he was avoiding a a hot
wire I guess yeah I guess so no that's
that is really cool though um and I
think I think it's awesome the tip that
he said about um trying things in
different states I think is really cool
especially for iot related stuff um
things really do change during software
updates on a pretty regular basis for
iot stuff so really great great takeway
there um Tesla hacking Tesla cars I
don't know man seems like there's a high
dup percentage there maybe it's just
because people are very interested in
the technology so they spend more time
looking at it or maybe it's because
their patch cycle is really slow but um
I don't know definitely something to to
be aware of um the other thing I I
really liked from this write up was uh
his persist
how motivated he was he poured over
diagrams he spent hours he was really
just hobbying it right um a lot of times
bug Bounty you kind of think about oh
well you know I'm not earning millions
of dollars doing B Bounty I'm not
succeeding it's not the case like try to
be a hobbyist about it you know before
bug Bounty people would just do this
[__] for fun you know um and and try not
to get arrested yeah so so like try try
to be a little bit more hobbyist about
it I think is a good takeaway and then
also he slows down and he shows full
impact once he has a a thing um a lead
and I think this is an interesting thing
because my experience in the bug Bounty
Arena has
said uh just go ahead and report it like
just I mean especially with something
like a car where they actually can't
patch it you know without your
permission just go ahead and report it
um and then add to the report when you
have when you fleshed out more impact uh
and but but don't stop right report it
and then keep moving because I think
it's easy for once you've kind of lost
your momentum a little bit when you went
went and wrote the report or whatever to
kind of like just wait and then kind of
get in that post report stall where
you're like uh I reported it I want to
see what they say before I spend more
time on it don't do that just keep keep
building out that impact if you think
the the possibility is there and um so
Props to Evan for for doing that fully I
like that yeah totally um all right well
speaking of that mental aspect right I
think that's that's kind of our topic
for today right yeah we've we've got a
good a good little um segment for that
today and actually we're already an hour
end so we should be on the lookout for
that but um I kind of wanted to
discuss staying sharp and motivated
inside of bug Bounty okay so I think
there's a couple there's a couple little
segments that I kind of broken this into
one um you know staying sharp and
motivated and and
two avoiding the opposite of that
avoiding burnout avoid avoiding um
getting stagnant or stale so we'll kind
of take that from two angles but first I
wanted to ask you something okay so I
was writing this out and I was like oh
you know what are some of the common
mistakes people make you know that kind
of get them to disappointed and kind of
get them in a rut with buck Bounty and I
think one of them is sort of getting a
really painful dupe or getting a really
painful n
informative and then just kind of
sitting in that Valley of Sorrow you
know um and I think maybe for for people
that are new to bug Bounty that don't
have a lot of self-confidence um in in
their abilities as as a book Bounty
Hunter then it could be good advice to
say like hey don't get your hopes up
until you see that that report mov to
triage or until you see that Bounty
report um you know or Bounty awarded in
your email um but for me as a more
experienced hacker I don't know maybe
it's just kind of like
um like like I I need to feel something
you know like from bug Bounty you know
like I just I just want to feel
something man um but I kind of like to
ride the highs and lows like I kind of
like to as soon as I find something
Freak Out run tell my wife jump up and
down scream and then you know when it's
a low I kind of like to you know flop on
the ground and like take some time go
sit in the hot tub drink my coffee be
all soulen or whatever and then you know
move through it because I think it it
kind of keeps things emotionally charged
for me which I think is more helpful in
the long term so what do you what do
what do you think about all that I mean
I guess it all just depends on like how
you
within process emotions right like some
people it's uh better for them to just
sort of like feel through it and let it
pass other people like I think generally
trying to stay positive about it is is
always a good thing like I'm definitely
not positive 100% of the time um I
definitely like uh like I almost quit
bug Bounty like a month ago so like I've
definitely been there you know um but um
I think uh especially around dupes just
one thing I want to note um is uh a lot
of people see dupe as a a failure uh a
dupe is
literally like you literally found a
valid bug like it's literally been
accepted by the program it's not a
failure the only thing that failed is
that you didn't get paid for it and the
only thing that you lost was your time
um so there's nothing really that you
can do about that but I would encourage
you to just you know try and stay
positive that like you
found uh you did find a valid bug that
was accepted by the program is you just
got you know screwed over by timing um
maybe I don't know just as food for
thought for some of the program people
who are or sorry the platform people who
are listening like from hacker one and
whatever um it might be interesting to
see some sort of shift on like the
framing of
duplicate and the fact that there's no
awards no nothing like at minimum it
listen if we're giving freaking points
for VDP like why aren't we giving points
for dupes come on give you like two
reputation points or something like that
but I think I think they want they want
to you know minimize gaming of the
system but it would be nice if there was
some additional system already gam yeah
seriously but but I mean like it would
be nice if there was some sort of
additional like um yeah framing around
in that surrounding that and and I don't
have a great suggestion for it but like
you said validating showing that it's a
valid bug like affirming the hacker that
sort of thing and I will say you know
you mentioned you do lose your time
which is true you know if you're looking
at it from a monetary perspective you do
lose your time but um also as a hacker
you kind of grow more with each bug and
you found a valid bug you submitted the
report it got duped that is what it is
but also that bug is a valid bug in your
repertoire as a hacker and you fully
exploited that you submitted a you
outlined it in a report you went through
the steps to do that so from like a
hacker development perspective it's not
a loss even though it can feel like a
loss because your wallet isn't thicker
yeah yeah and like being failure vers is
totally normal um like I think that's a
good instinct to have of like not
wanting to get a dupe and not wanting to
like have something fall through like
that that's totally normal um you know
loss of version failure version all that
kind of stuff like it's very very normal
um so I don't know Joel you and I you
we've debated this on the Pod before but
whenever I hear you say failure aversion
is is a good thing like no I'm not
necessarily necessarily saying it's a
good thing but it's a it's a normal
thing it like to some extent it can be
good like if you let it control you then
and like you ignore like like you need
to be able to push through it in some
cases right like um in most cases I
would
say and yeah like it depends on the goal
right like it depends on what the what
the outcome is and you know probably in
in the cases that we're talking about
for like bug Bounty where it's like more
of a mental thing thing than it is any
like actual loss um or like failure then
it's like yeah like just you know the
worst thing that happens is that your
book gets closed uh or lowered in
severity does that suck yes is that
worth not reporting it is that not worth
like not following through on it no like
because the financial incentive is there
is still like a potential large upside
yeah yeah I agree yeah it's it's a
little bit tricky with the failure
version thing because my my my
experience with failure version is like
I think it's one of the things that most
people do not have the uh that muscle
sort of developed and flexed and
essentially the first thing I tell all
of my mentes is like listen you are
going to fail 98% of the time as a
extremely talented hacker like as a top
tier hacker your success rate is going
to be like 2% on the attack vectors that
you implement right um and you know this
varies with your you know if you're
doing white box then sure you might be
more but um you know as a blackbox
texter you have to test everything
you're going to fail all the time um and
it's it's going to suck so you have to
build out that that whole concept of
like a failure should be redefined as
something where you where you can now
affirmatively say this doesn't work and
cross that off the list and feel like
you've made progress um that reframing
is absolutely essential I think for
staying sharp and motivated um and and
on top of Bo County um yeah yeah I mean
like we encounter quote unquote like
failures all the time right it just
depends on how you view it it's like is
testing for rce and command injection on
like the I on the CMD parameter if that
doesn't work is that a failure no that's
like that's like uh extremely that's
like roll that's like gambling you know
what I mean it's like uh you know don't
get outad of yourself if you lose at the
casino because like it's literally like
everything is a gamble everything is a
test
um but the difference between gambling
and bu Bing is that you can actually
learn from the signals that you see in
response and you can actually influence
those and change them it's not
completely pure chance yeah yeah I agree
um all right so let's move into the
staying sharp and motivated uh section
and then we'll kind of move over to the
the burnout avoidance um before we get
into the things that are actually like
sort of buck Bounty related uh do you
know what a continuous glucose monitor
is I I do and when I saw CGM I was like
is that what I mean yes it is what I
mean it's like what what does he mean by
this so it's like you know I mean CGM
might help with your your staying sharp
and motivated well that's what I'm
saying like like so so I um I've got one
sitting right over there but I I got one
the other day yeah yeah I I I had one in
my arm for two weeks and I I got it just
as a way to monitor my blood glucose
levels and see how I respond to various
Foods so I can did you get the huberman
one no I didn't I didn't I got one like
prescribed through my doctor I said hey
can you prescribe me one he's like sure
um and so I I I got it hooked up to the
app and um and it was really interesting
to see like how fasting plus coffee gets
me in this super like locked in uh
focused state for a while but then it
sort of tails off towards the end and
then what I found is so I eat a lot of
rice because we lived in Japan and we
got used to that diet and we just kind
of haven't shifted away from it um a and
and so uh when I eat a bowl of white
rice
that just messes with me dude like my my
blood glucose levels just Skyrocket and
then Plum it and I'm like you know why
that is well I mean it's a it's I mean
explain it to me no I don't know why it
is well it's all gluten it's like yeah
cuz it's it's grain right so it gets
converted it's from gets converted from
gluten into glucose and then uh your
body has like a massive sugar Spike and
then it has a massive sugar crash right
after um cuz there's no like you're
going from nothing to something to
nothing yeah and I know those carbs all
sort of break down into that and and so
I didn't do as much analysis on it as I
as I should have because I got super
busy in those two weeks but um I thought
it was a really interesting sort of
experiment to say like okay this is how
uh various Foods at certain timings
affect my body and like keep me in a
state of being focused or in a state
where I can't focus and I'm just super
exhausted and dying and falling over so
um I I really recommend it I think mine
I think I got four weeks worth of uh
continuous schol close monitors which is
two of them um and it was only like 70
bucks um which I think is a pretty good
investment so uh recommend that to
anyone who's interested in kind of uh
getting addressing this sort of
sharpness and mental Clarity from you do
intermittent fasting so yes sort of I I
don't do it on purpose but I I I don't
normally eat breakfast and I don't eat
late at night after I don't eat after
8:00 p.m. uh just as like a a family
thing um and so I end up doing roughly
an 816 intermittent fast um uh and so
yeah I think it really helps I do eat
lunch but I don't normally eat till like
two or
three okay interesting okay so we have
probably about pretty similar I don't I
eat once a day usually like what but at
like 2:00 or 3: yeah so I don't eat
breakfast I don't eat lunch I eat dinner
at like 300 or 4 really and then like
um usually what ends up happening though
is I end up like snacking a lot um after
that um so that probably isn't great
either but yeah I've always wondered
what my um glucose levels would look
like just monitoring them because I
don't eat anything until like the late
afternoon and I know that like I crash
um pretty hard like and the same thing
happens to me where like I'll eat and
then I'll crash and so like I it it
doesn't like improve my energy levels at
all when I eat dinner I just like I'm
kind of putting off this eating a little
bit cuz it's like okay I know as soon as
I eat I'm not going to be able to hack
or I'm not going to be able to do
anything so it's like it's very
important I think for me to understand
okay what kind of um food should I eat
that keeps me sharp and and keeps me
able to be engaged through the full work
day um and to be honest even if I didn't
the productivity uh tradeoffs in the
morning uh are pretty strong like I feel
like I I get at least 8 hours worth of
of work done you know by like two or
three by the time I I first eat um and
so I I think it's really helpful but
it'd be even more helpful if I could
prevent that crash and um that
definitely depends on what kind of foods
I'm eating and then also whether I'm
going for a walk or getting some
exercise immediately following getting
some food in me yeah yeah and I think
also just having like the right things
around for you to have available like
for me um like my ADHD makes it really
hard for me to like plan or like food or
like want to like make food and stuff
especially when I'm in the middle of
stuff like I hate getting interrupted
and like task like switching and stuff
so um it's uh if there's like nothing
readily available for me to just like
grab like a bag of like you know beef
jerky or something like I'm just like I
just won't eat or I just like won't have
anything until like I'm like starving
yeah it it It's Tricky it's something
you definitely got to be aware of and um
I've got a buddy actually that recently
started a business here in Richmond so
if any of you guys are in Richmond and
are interested in this then DM me but uh
he does sort of a private cheal prep
yeah like exactly I've actually done
this before have you really yeah yeah
yeah I Ed somebody for that back in
California um and the pricing like
wasn't bad at all honestly the hardest
thing for me was like the calories like
a lot of these types of things are
generally like designed for people who
are like trying to monitor their caloric
intake so you're going to see like
somewhere between 4 and 600 maybe 800
calories per meal um and unless you're
eating like four of those a day uh
you're not going to hit like your normal
consumption unless you're trying to cook
calories um so that can be a lot but
like as little quick meals that you
throw in the microwave like you know
it's up like either like have somebody
you know deliver it to your door or like
do that on the weekend and like portion
out like broccoli and bits of chicken
and steak and whatever whatever you eat
and then just like throw it little
microwave food boxes and then stack them
in the fridge and you're good to go yeah
yeah no absolutely and I think you know
what my buddy does is he he does it a
little bit it's more of a high-end
service um uh but but still pretty
pretty uh well priced I must say where
he he will take in into account all
those things if you say Okay I want you
know one meal that's 2,000 calories you
know right like if you're eating one
meal a day or whatever right then he can
make that happen or if it's like I want
smaller meals of this amount I want
these macros I prefer these meats you
know that sort of thing um he can kind
of make it happen to a certain degree
you know it still got to make sense from
him from like a aive scale perspec get
the recipe for the 2,000 calorie meal
you know that's that's me saying like
you know because he does have some
customers he mentioned to me that are
like pretty serious um you know
bodybuilding types that need to consume
a lot of calories uh and so um it all
depends on what your your individual
diet looks like but now now we've kind
of they're Mar the end of our and lab uh
critical thinking the point is like
there are there are like a couple things
that I feel very strongly about that
like when I was younger I used to um I I
didn't give a [__] about what I ate I
didn't give a [__] about when or how
much I slept um
and I didn't give a [__] about when or
how much C caffeine I consumed and those
three things alone are like
huge
um modifiers to how you're going to feel
every single day yeah like when you
choose to drink coffee like uh you
should wait like probably an hour to an
hour and a half after you wake up before
you have any any caffeine you shouldn't
have any like at most or at minimum six
hours before you go to bed probably like
8 to 12 um you should be sleeping at
least six hours probably 6 to nine
depending on age gender
Etc and you should be going to bed and
waking up at the same exact time when I
was in college I used to like go to bed
at like I don't know like 3:00 a.m. wake
up at like 6 like or like whatever like
I was just like sleeping Whenever
However much I didn't like have alarms H
go to bed at the same time wake up at
the same time even on the weekends sleep
enough respect your sleep if you do not
respect your sleep your sleep will not
respect you and it will [__] you up oh
man you want to you want to you want to
like lower your life expectancy start
sleeping four hours a night like my
goodness that is uh yeah straight up I
take my I take my whis eat my coffee
black and my bed at 3 and I'm going to
die soon three wow no no I I I I go to
bed at like 10 so um you can go to bed
at 5:00 a.m. if you do it every night I
wouldn't necessarily recommend it
because yeah like you know there are
still like circadian rhythm things that
like you know going to bed like when the
sun comes out like third shift third
shift work is classified as cogenic in
the US because it's so bad for you yeah
the the hit to your your Cadian rhythm
is so bad that it get it's shown to
cause cancer um so you know like there
are there are definitely like certain
things that you might want to avoid but
I think like having schedules and like
standards for your sleep and routine is
like probably the bare minimum you
should do for your body yeah no I I
totally agree so keep keeping I guess
bringing that all back around to the
topic at hand being aware especially if
you're doing this full-time um being
aware of what you're you know what
habits you're falling into place are
falling into place when you're eating
how much you're eating what you're
eating caus cusing you know various
effects on your energy I think is really
helpful for staying sharp and motivated
um uh the next one that I had sort of on
the list here is competition and
accountability when helpful so I think
just pulling some of the top hackers uh
that I've I've spoken with over the over
the past couple years um there are a lot
of people that really Thrive off of the
competition of bug Bounty uh Thrive off
of the leaderboards Thrive off of the
live hacking events it's it's something
that keeps them really motivated and uh
excited
so um I think that for the record I'm
not one of those people by the way I I
kind of wish I was sometimes but um and
I think a lot of a lot of the really top
people are
um maybe I used to be at some point but
I'm definitely not anymore yeah you know
it can change with time too I definitely
used to be more more competition
oriented and then I think um you know as
you start to understand more the nuances
of the system of like oh wow I actually
didn't really try that hard at that live
hacking event and I placed well uh you
start to realize that um there's a
certain degree of it that is just being
at the right place at the right time put
hours that sort of thing um yeah finding
the right bug like absolutely but but I
mean there is absolutely results that
that suggests the that people can do it
on a on a regular basis as well you know
like pretty much every every uh live
hacking event that I've seen frons
really give it his all he's he's at the
top you know um yeah for sure so I think
there there's definitely some some
aspect to this uh so figure out what
comp if competition motivates you set
friendly competitions with your with
your um you know other hackers and if
accountability could be motivating for
you then maybe something that I've seen
attack uh you know full-time bug bounty
hunters do is set
like set up an accountability schedule
with other Hunters um to be like okay
making sure I'm getting a certain number
of hacking hours in per week and that
sort of thing um and I've seen this be
helpful and it's been helpful for me in
the past when I've been trying to be um
when I've been less motivated to hack
and wanted to perform so um yeah you
know tweet out your weekly stats or
whatever like keep track of it in a
spreadsheet uh whatever you need to do
to like help you stay on track or feel
like you're you know hitting the goals
that you want to hit like um I think
it's always good to set goals so that
you have some sort of objective um
measurable marker on whether or not
you've hit that and when you're setting
those goals make sure it is something
that you can measure so it and don't
like be unfair to yourself don't be like
I want to make $500,000 this week
because like one maybe you will but like
the odds of you not are probably higher
than the odds of you are um and while
that's a good goal to set it's kind of
unrealistic and uh if you make $10,000
and then you compare that to the fact
that you wanted to make 500,000 you be
like wow I really sucked and didn't hit
my goal and it's like no bro you made
$10,000 this week you're fine um so I
think you know setting goals being
realistic about them um and having a
good perspective for uh you know where
your performance is and having
measurable goals is is really important
yeah absolutely and that just goes to a
lot of the whole self-help Theory as
well of like uh smart goals or whatever
and and so that's that is definitely
applicable here as well um the next one
that I had is working on something
interesting and or something that you're
interested in and I kind of wanted to
get your take on this as as somebody who
uh you know struggles with ADHD and and
weaponizes that and and also feels the
consequences of that um in your life um
so I think if for me even as somebody
that doesn't really super struggle with
that I think I perform much better when
I'm super engaged in something and if
you have the the flexibility to be like
okay I'm gonna go work on this thing and
then I'm gonna jump back to this thing
and I'm gonna you know and as your sort
of interest in certain tasks EB and flow
if you have the flexibility to work on
something that you're interested in I
think your brain is in more high
performance mode in those scenarios um
and I've definitely heard of people that
that have ADHD being able to weaponize
this pretty
effectively yeah so I think like being
able to focus in on something is
important like I I think generally it is
possible even with ADHD to like find
interest in something but a lot of bug
Bounty and a lot of I mean a lot of
everything that you do but you know bug
Bounty especially relies around the
mental that you have like like during
that moment like you said when France
decides that he's going to give it his
all in an event he's he ends up in the
top five top 10 top three
because it's commitment right he's not
there's no like oh let me do this other
thing he's committed like he is like
head down committed and fully 100% 150%
giving everything he has to trying and
finding the coolest best bugs that he
can um and he's working his brain in
overtime to try and you know make that
happen um so a lot of it is around how
you're mentally framing the entire
situation in your head are you taking
this seriously is this a Target you want
to hack or is this are you just like
trying to find an xss um you know I
think some like to some degree you do
need that interest to be like yeah okay
I want I like I want to hack this target
I want to find a bug here um if you're
somebody who does it full-time you're
not going to find that for every Target
I'm sure so um there is a whole other
side to it which is just like I'm I need
I want to find this xss because I need
to find this xss for my stats and that's
like a different you know but regardless
like you need to have some sort of
motivation that like pushes you to hack
on that Target if you're like I don't
want to be here the whole time that
you're hacking on that Target you're not
going to be really looking you're not
going to find um the gadgets and the and
the the you're not going to notice the
things that you need to notice so I'm
I'm going to jump one item down in the
list here Joel um and say and say
something that's sort of contradictory
to what I just said which is I think
there's also a lot of Merit
in staying on the same Target longer
than you feel like staying on the same
Target um from a motivation perspective
because um what what it forces you to do
is it forces you to look at a target
from a different angle and once you've
done that a couple times and you sort of
flexed that muscle it's not going to
feel like you're sharp and motivated the
first time a couple times you do it
right but once you've sort of flexed
that muscle a little bit you start to
realize that you miss stuff
everywhere
everywhere all over the place everyone
does it's just a it's just a part of the
breadth of the the whole you know app
ecosystem and and just how bug Bounty
Works in general is you're going to miss
stuff um and that's why there's always
stuff to find um so I I think forcing
yourself to take a deep breath sort of
um write down or quantify what sort of
things you've actually tried on this
applic and what sort of things you
haven't and then coming at it at a
different angle in the long term will
give you motivation um payoff because
you'll start to realize hey even when I
feel like I've hit a wall there is more
there and I know that because it there
was more there this time and this time
and this time and this time when I did
it and um the evidence suggests that
this is this case is no different um
yeah yeah what what are your thoughts on
yeah absolutely well well and like this
one thing that we talk about time is
taking notes and I think like taking
notes in the beginning um or just like
throughout the whole process is really
good for chasing down and like pushing
yourself to whether it's a Time minimum
um or just like taking really diligent
notes and you know checking every single
path or whatever like um you know you
you want like you said you want to push
yourself to actually feel like you're
done before you move on with with
something um but you also don't need to
like be excessive with it so that part
of that is going to be a time thing as
you hack more you'll gain that sense and
you'll be able to you know better judge
when it's time to move on um but even
you know even still like both of us take
notes everybody takes notes and and you
know circles back and goes okay what
didn't I look at here um and having
having a way to look at that is really
important yeah I'll of I'll often take
retrospective notes dude like I'll I'll
like just go hey I'm on a target for two
hours and then I'll say all right what
have I learned about this Target and
I'll write that down and what I I've
actually started doing as I started
having some more um hard stop times uh
just as my life became a little bit less
flexible um I I've started taking Loom
videos of myself talking about a Target
and and just I'll I'll sort of just
brain dump on myself uh essentially try
to give any information that will get
future Justin back in the same heads
space as he was um you know when he
stopped hacking uh and and watching
those videos as soon as I start the next
hacking session and that that really
really helps um and and I think this
that one is specifically applicable for
people that do part-time hunting and
might not be able to hack every day and
might have to stop for longer periods of
time having that in place as a habit
will allow you to reduce the amount of
time that you spend uh sort of trying to
reignite your your your uh interest in a
Target and getting back in your Flow
State um so that's that's a great one as
well um the next two that I wanted to
talk about uh gadgets and then goals and
celebrations both of these sort of speak
to motivation and controlling your own
motivation one recognizing when you
found a gadget and celebrating that win
I think is really good um it it will
keep your momentum going it'll keep you
feeling like you're making progress even
if you don't have a report to send in so
we talked about that a lot so I'm going
to leave that one there and then the
other one is is goals and celebrations
so um my wife and I do this for every
live hacking event that I do we select
some sort of thing I'm going to do if I
crushed this live hacking event like all
I'm gonna you know my hot tub was one of
them uh you know that I really had to
that was a stretch goal I had to really
hustle for that one um and you know
sometimes it's as simple as going out to
a super fancy dinner with me and her um
you know just going blocking off that
time not thinking about money or
anything just saying okay this is a
reward for a job well done um but
defining those those goals and getting
those in place and time bounding those
um really motivating for me uh to to get
done what I want to get done yeah for
sure and again this goes back to setting
good measurable goals for yourself that
are realistic and that you can achieve
um do this is a strategy I do every
single day like if I have completed
something and I haven't put it on my
to-do list I'll put it on my to-do list
and check it off just to be like yeah I
did something today um like it's really
important to feel completion and feel
like you've accomplished things and done
things and made progress especially on
those days where it feels like you
aren't right like if you feel like you
like if you haven't submitted anything
or you haven't the done X Y and Z like
make a list of the things that you did
do today and just go and check them off
and be like oh yeah actually I did do a
bunch of stuff today um and and you know
just put stuff in perspective because
especially with bug Bounty especially
when you're working alone it's really
easy to just spend eight hours like
focusing on your computer screen and
then be like oh [__] it's 3 o' like I
have no idea what I did today but I
didn't submit anything so it feels like
I did nothing yeah yeah and I I'll sort
of share a vulnerable story about this I
mean last night I texted you probably 10
10 p.m. saying hey man uh I didn't get
the notes fully prepped for this episode
today like I I normally do I'm going to
wake up early tomorrow morning and do it
and the reason for that was I got super
fixated on a task yesterday and I was
and it was a big task and I performed
super well on it I got a ton of work
done on it and I I'm really grateful
that that I did and that I was that
motivated on that day but I did not
prioritize the thing that I needed to
get done for this morning and that has
effects on on you and it has effects on
you know other people too luckily I was
able to get out of bed this morning and
get another hour or so of prep in before
the episode um but I think there's also
something to be said
about knowing what times you have
flexibility and and living in that
flexibility especially as a full-time
Hunter that's a great benefit of our our
sort of life that we lead um but then
also knowing hey there are times I need
to write down my tasks and I need I need
to prioritize the thing that will that
are time sensitive that will give
Forten and then just crank it out you
know and just hit it boom boom boom boom
boom and I think wisdom sort of should
dictate what what time is
what yeah and I think you'd be really
hardpressed to find anybody who like has
never procrastinated or has never like
spent time doing something that they
shouldn't have done like it can be
difficult I salute the people who can
just immediately be like okay I need to
work on this thing I'm going to go work
on this thing regardless of what time or
how I feel and go do that thing I'm not
one of those people either like I can
depending on what it is I've definitely
sat down and been like [__] I need to do
this work thing for tomorrow and it's 7
o'clock i' sit down I open my laptop and
I do it because you know that's that's
life sometimes right like you sleep in
the bed that you make for yourself so if
if that's something that's my fault and
I put it off like absolutely um you got
to own that uh you gotta you know
sometimes you you have to uh bite the
bullet and you got to do tough things
because uh you made a bad decision at a
different time and that's the
consequence um but not always right and
so um you know just this goes a little
bit into the burnout stuff but like uh I
think one really big burnout philosophy
I have is like don't be uh if you're own
if you're Your Own Boss especially with
like free time uh don't be your own
[__] boss don't be like the guy who's
just
like get back to work it's the weekend
like get like you're allowed to have
days off like I'm going to need this TPS
report by
Saturday
yeah hey yeah so I mean yeah a lot of um
you know like be fair to yourself be
fair to your time be fair to your energy
don't um you know there's a line that
you should draw for yourself in terms of
where am I going to force myself and
push myself to go beyond my limits um
and it's okay to some days drop that
line to a different level um and it's
okay to have sick days and it's okay to
take time off and um it's okay to you
know give yourself some some Grace
because uh it's hard to be self-employed
it's hard to work all the time and with
bug Bounty it feel it can definitely
feel like especially full-time bug
Bounty it can feel like a rat race where
you're just like constantly on the wheel
and if you're not on the wheel uh you're
not making money and you're not
submitting bugs and everything comes to
a halt and um getting out of that
mindset be really difficult it is it is
It's Tricky and uh yeah I totally
seconded everything you just said about
that um and and so I'm going to I'm
going to jump through some of these
other ones we kind of touched on
collaboration already but of course
collaboration can really keep you sharp
and motivated um uh working with other
hackers grabbing little tidbits and and
one note I will add on collaborations um
if you want to be a really good
collaborator if that's something that
you want to improve on as a hacker uh
take your partners
bugs gadgets weird functionality take
that really seriously like if if
somebody sends you something says hey
look at this this is kind of sketchy
right like and you get to it and you
don't see the sketchiness right away
don't just write it off like try to see
the sketchiness and try to iterate on
that try to get excited with them about
it um because we all have different
lenses and especially if you're
collaborating with someone you respect
which I you should always do I think um
then
they might see something that you don't
and you got to acknowledge that
um in addition so totally different
angle but also work with high quality
teams high quality programs programs
that are going to give you fast
communication programs that are going to
validate your threat model your
understanding of their threat model
quickly because um that will there's
nothing more motivating than a program
coming back and saying wow that report
was a banger you know like we're shaking
in our boots over here you know I and I
I think if there's anyone from the
program side listening of course I mean
Joel is here so he knows what's up but
um you know providing that little bit of
encouragement to the hackers saying you
know and really playing into the how the
hacker wants to feel like oh [__] you
know that one really got us you know
scrambling or something like that can be
a massive motivator for the hackers um
and so working with the teams that that
give you that and for teams make sure
you're giving that to the hacker because
that's one way for sure to keep loyalty
to your program yeah yeah I totally
agree I mean it right it's like a
two-way street you know um from the
researchers perspective like um somebody
has to extend their hand first in a
handshake you know like um and both
parties have to do it for it to happen
and so it does take some some
cooperation and some you know
um like I don't know I think a good
analogy is like if you've ever had a
conversation with someone uh who like
doesn't carry their side of the
conversation it's never fun and it
doesn't feel like a fulfilling
conversation you're probably not going
to want to have another conversation
with that person and that goes the same
way for a report like if you provide
like very minimal like just like shorten
to the point unless you're consistently
doing that type of research the the
program is probably not going to be like
wow like great research but like if you
go out of your way out from the gate to
like demonstrate that you're like a
quality researcher there's a lot of like
thought and time and effort and energy
put into your hacking like the program
will acknowledge that should acknowledge
that and and respect that and um
appreciate that first impressions in bug
Bounty are also important you know that
first that first report comes through
with a real with a real Banger as much
as feel like a dad on this episode I'm
just giving life
tips sleep at an appropriate time Justin
and Joel your bug Bounty dads don't
drink
coffee that sounds like we're a gay
couple like your bug Bounty dads uh no
um so we're both married uh not the
there's anything wrong with that but uh
yeah uh so anyway the the last thing
that I had on the list here um was
routine reducing the friction in your
workflow right um and I wanted to to
talk about this one because there's
friction in everybody's workflow right
um there's there's areas where uh you
are having to do something manually
you're testing something um uh that just
takes more time to go through the the
Hoops to do it uh and there's there's
some way that you can automate it and
make it better uh and I think one of the
things that really helps me from a
motivation perspective is taking the
time every couple weeks whenever I see
these sort of things popping up just
dropping them in my certain project in
my to-do list um uh and actually taking
the time to actually Implement those and
then appreciate them as soon as you're
actually using them right like wow I
just right clicked and selected this
thing and it automatically did it this
rocks um like I guarantee it's it's
going to be one of those things that
every time you use that tool you're
going to be like wow this is so much
easier I should have done that M like
wow this is so nice that I just run this
one command or just give it these three
arguments why didn't I do that earlier
and I think a lot of it for me a lot of
the time is do I really want to spend
that time like writing this thing like I
I I'll just do I just want to follow
this bug and like again like follow the
energy like ride the highs like ride the
lows but also know when to spend your
time fixing
a problem and like fix things that are
annoying to you right it's like a
squeaky door you know you get the hinge
you open you open that one door in your
house and every time you open it it
squeaks and you don't realize it bothers
you but now that I've said it I
guarantee you're going to go open a door
you're going to be like [__] that H dude
I went go get some oil and oil the
hinge it takes 5 seconds I went on a
vacation uh this past weekend and the
house that I went to the stairs were
silent like you walk up the stairs and
nothing nothing you hear no squeaks
right and I was like was it just built
like no it wasn't and it's it was a
Beach property as well so I'm like no
idea how they did that but like I get
back to my house and I'm like walk up
the stairs I'm hearing I'm like Strat
you know like back on the construction
combo I have a feeling I know what they
did here okay it's it's a three three
part combo Nails screws and glue all
three you'll you're it'll never squeak
but you'll also never get a off yeah
yeah well you know at this point I I'll
take him off do something to him at some
point because it's driving me nuts um
but okay so that's the end of the uh
staying sharp and motivated section
let's move into the burnout avoidance um
I think I only have a couple little
little tips here and I've kind of talked
about my ideology about this a couple
times I think the number one thing that
helps me avoid burnout as a full-time
hacker for nearly 5 years now is not
putting myself worth into uh hacking
okay so if you are the kind of person
that says wow uh I think less of myself
if I haven't found a bug recently or I
think less of myself if um you know I'm
I'm not ranking in the top you know
whatever percent in a live hacking event
um you should really try to minimize
that as much as you can I will say you
might lose some competitive uh Edge if
you do that but my experience has
actually been the opposite when you sort
of Disconnect from that you put yourself
worth in something more consistent uh
I'll just say intrinsic something that
is not as unstable right something that
you control internally um then that will
be a lot better for your your mental
health and your grass have a hobby yeah
and make children
absolutely have sex have well don't you
don't have to make children get children
uh adopt children okay this is getting
out of head exactly so you know there's
lots of lots of ways to do that but I
think having an intrinsic self-worth
indicator is really important taking
breaks like you said having Hobbies
doing something outside of bug Bounty
because and here's the tricky thing dude
because when you go full-time bug Bounty
um probably what happened is your hobby
just became your job um and when that
happens it's very hard to reallocate
that time and SP mental space because
and that's great because you love your
job and you're you're doing your job
that you love every day and it's
wonderful um but also you have to make
space for other things so uh make sure
you're doing that intentionally if
you're a full-time Hunter because uh it
will bite you in the butt if you don't
um yeah yeah the one little anecdote
I'll I'll I'll leave with and I think we
we probably because close on time but um
I do have a friend who he uh probably a
year or two ago he completely pivoted
into a into a different job um from one
thing into something completely opposite
he did it very diligently for a year and
a half or two years and then um recently
he was like you know this was a mistake
actually um you know I realized that
after after doing this for a while like
it's a really big grind the drawbacks
where where there are drawbacks are huge
and the upsides are huge too but it's
not worth it it's not giving me fillment
and joy in the way that I wanted it to
and so he's going back he's going back
to doing what he was before I would say
like it's important to um to be real
with yourself about turning something
that you enjoy into a job and what that
means to the Rel relationship you have
with that thing um whether that's a
hobby whether that's um a side project a
part-time job bug b anything like if you
decide to um if you decide to turn that
into something that's going to be your
source of income it's going to change
the way that you view it and when you
wake up and have to do it to make money
instead of waking up and getting to do
it because it's fun it's very different
yeah totally agree man all right I know
you got to bounce we got a hard stop
that's a wrap
and that's a wrap on this episode of
critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to CT bb.
show/ Discord join the Discord there's
lots of great conversations and chats
going on over there and if you want to
support the show there's the Discord
subscriber tiers which give you access
to master classes amas hack along alongs
exclusive scripts and an exclusive chat
Channel with us we'll see you there